{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following techniques was carried out by Nirenberg and Matthaei in 1961 to determine the first codon?", "opta": "In vitro synthesis of a polypeptide using UUUUU", "optb": "Labeled peptide binding to a ribosome", "optc": "Mixed co-polymer mRNA synthesis", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacterial protein called catabolic activator protein (CAP) is an example of", "opta": "negative control of gene expression", "optb": "positive control of gene expression", "optc": "second type of positive control of gene expression", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many different codons are possible?", "opta": "3", "optb": "20", "optc": "64", "optd": "An infinite number", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The genetic code is", "opta": "universal", "optb": "universal except for rare exceptions in mitochondria and some protozoa", "optc": "species-specific", "optd": "kingdom-specific", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following has been used as an evidence that primitive life forms lacked both DNA and enzymes?", "opta": "RNA can both code genetic information and act as a catalyst", "optb": "DNA and enzymes are only present in the most advanced cells", "optc": "Advanced cells lack RNA", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Crick demonstrated that the genetic code involved three bases and suggested that the code was degenerated. What experimental technique Crick conducted to suggest genetic code degeneration?", "opta": "Gel electrophoresis", "optb": "Density gradient centrifugation", "optc": "Frameshift mutagenesis", "optd": "Restriction digests of the rII gene", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Codon that specify the amino acids often differs in the", "opta": "first base", "optb": "second base", "optc": "third base", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In some organelles in eukaryotes, the genetic code for some codons", "opta": "differs from that used in prokaryotes", "optb": "are same", "optc": "are partially same", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The codons which do not specify an amino acid are called", "opta": "initiation code", "optb": "termination code", "optc": "propagation code", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The genetic code is degenerated. Which of the following codons represents the principle of degeneracy?", "opta": "UAA and UAC", "optb": "AUG and AUA", "optc": "CAU and CAC", "optd": "UUA and UUC", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sequence of one strand of DNA is: 5' ATTGCCA 3', what is the sequence of the other strand?", "opta": "5' TAACGGT 3'", "optb": "5' TGGCAAT 3'", "optc": "5' ATTGCCA 3'", "optd": "5' UAAGCCU3'", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In prokaryotes, AUG encodes", "opta": "methionine", "optb": "N-formyl methionine", "optc": "a stop codon", "optd": "alanine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many amino acids will be encoded by 5' GAU GGU UGA UGU 3' sequence?", "opta": "One", "optb": "Two", "optc": "Three", "optd": "Four", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In protein synthesis in prokaryotes", "opta": "the initiating amino acid is N- formyl methionine", "optb": "the initiating amino acid is methionine", "optc": "the initiating amino acid is phenyl alanine", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "AUG codes for methionine act as a", "opta": "initiation code", "optb": "elongation code", "optc": "termination code", "optd": "propagation code", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Translation begins", "opta": "at the replication fork", "optb": "on the lagging strand", "optc": "at the start codon", "optd": "in nucleus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}